<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi! I&#39;m Wilson.</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hi! I&#39;m Wilson.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 21:25:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Orange Pi Zero3 Device Tree Overlay</title>
      <link>/posts/orange-pi-zero3-device-tree-overlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 21:25:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/orange-pi-zero3-device-tree-overlay/</guid>
      <description>The Orange Pi Zero3 includes 13 GPIOs dedicated to an expansion shield (pictured below).&#xA;However, the first time I tried using one of the USB ports on it I got no response at all from the system. This post outlines the steps necessary to enable the 13-pin expansion shield on the Zero3.&#xA;USB2, USB3, and CIR on the Allwinner H616/H618 We first need to figure out how the 13 expansion GPIOs are connected to our SOC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Headers for Orange Pi Zero3</title>
      <link>/posts/linux-headers-for-orange-pi-zero3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:30:10 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/linux-headers-for-orange-pi-zero3/</guid>
      <description>After successfully bringing up my Zero3 I wanted to learn more about kernel module development. While following along with an introductory tutorial I wrote a makefile to handle the compilation of .c files into .ko files that I could load. The makefile was fairly simple - it had a single recipe for compiling the module:&#xA;obj-m += mymodule.o all: make -C /lib/modules/$(shell uname -r)/build M=$(PWD) modules Seems simple, right? All we&amp;rsquo;re doing is using the contents of build to compile a kernel module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Board Bringup for Orange Pi Zero3 (Part 2)</title>
      <link>/posts/opi_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 13:17:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/opi_part2/</guid>
      <description>At this stage, you should have a partitioned and formatted micro-SD card with u-boot loaded on the first partition. Your project directory should look something like this:&#xA;opi-image/ | - - linux/ | - - u-boot/ | - - arm-trusted-firmware/ | - - linux-firmware/ Please note that these instructions assume you are running on arm64 architecture.&#xA;Configure the Kernel Navigate into linux/ and run the following command:&#xA;ARCH=arm64 CROSS_COMPILE=aarch64-linux-gnu- make defconfig If all you want is the barebones linux kernel, then skip this next part.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Board Bringup for Orange Pi Zero3 (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/posts/opi_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 13:16:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/opi_part1/</guid>
      <description>I recently purchased an Orange Pi Zero3 so that I&amp;rsquo;d have a platform for IoT-based projects I have planned. My evaluation process at the time of purchase was fairly simple:&#xA;this board is pretty powerful this board can connect to the internet this board is cheap-ish (~30$) Once it arrived I began to realize that my evaluation process was&amp;hellip;slightly flawed.&#xA;The first sign of trouble came when I searched for an OS that would run on the board.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an SDK for the ESP-01/ESP8266</title>
      <link>/posts/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 11:49:23 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/first_post/</guid>
      <description>ESP-OPEN-SDK on the Raspberry Pi 4B Table of Contents Introduction My Environment Espressif&amp;rsquo;s Official SDK Enter the ESP-OPEN-SDK Fix the Bash version issue Fix the ISL Library URL Fix the Expat Version Fix a GCC/C++ compatability issue Fix a Python internal API issue Fix the esptool.py issue C&amp;rsquo;est Fini! Notes Introduction Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on honing my skills as a developer, both in coding but also in my development environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/index-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/index-about/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for checking out my portfolio.&#xA;You can read more about me here or take a look at my projects here.&#xA;I also write posts relating to the projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on (or just random issues I come across while I&amp;rsquo;m tinkering). You can read those here.&#xA;Are you hiring? I&amp;rsquo;m currently open to new opportunities.&#xA;You can contact me on LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
